Inventory of the Eugenio Cortez Collection, 1893-1900, 1914-1918 and undated
Eugenio Cortez Collection
Cortez, Eugenio.
MS 356
2 linear feet
The University of Texas at San Antonio Libraries Special Collections.
The Cortez family moved from San Diego, Texas to San Antonio, Texas.
The collection consists of 30 photographs documenting landmarks in San Diego, TX and San Antonio, TX as well as Eugenio Cortez's family members.
Biographical Note
The Cortez family moved from San Diego, Texas to San Antonio, Texas.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of 30 photographs documenting landmarks in San Diego, TX and San Antonio, TX as well as Eugenio Cortez's family members.
Access Restrictions
This collection is housed at UTSA's Main Campus and must be accessed via the John Peace Library Special Collections reading room. To request access, please use the Collections Request Form.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Eugenio Cortez at the date of accessioning.
Acquisition Information
Donated in July 2011 (2011-030).
Index Terms
Personal Names
Cortez, Eugenio
Locations
San Antonio (Tex.); San Diego (Tex.)
Genres/Formats
Photographs.
Local Subjects
Photographs/Photography; San Antonio History
- Eugenio Cortez collection
  - Autograph album (San Diego, Texas), 1893-1894 (Box OM1)
  - "Humor" scrapbook of comics, undated (Box OM1)
  - Archie Gunn "If Wishes Came True" postcard, undated (Box OM1)
  - Photograph, ["Maggie and Ona", "San Pedro Park for a day's outing"], February 22, 1900 (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard [note from Mercedes Resendez to Cesilia Garza de Gonzales, pictured: Mercedes Resendez], August 29, 1914 (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard [pictured: Jose Garza Jimenez, 32 years, Maria de los Angeles 4 years, San Antonio], July 14, 1914 (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard, unidentified couple [2 copies, 1 addressed to Cecilia G. de Garza and signed by Micaela G. de Jimenez, the other addressed to Maria Gonzalez and signed by Micaela G. de Jimenez], undated (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard [from Maria Queroga to Jose G. Jimenez, pictured: 13 year old daughter of Maria Queroga], May 15, 1917 (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard [pictured: Virginia, daughter of Jose and Virginia, 21 months], April 22, 1918 (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard[pictured: Roberto de los Santos y Esposato, 2 years 1 month], undated (Box OM1)
  - Tinted photograph [pictured: Carolina Peña], undated (Box OM1)
  - Unidentified family photograph [2 adults, 4 children], undated (Box OM1)
  - Unidentified family photograph, undated (Box OM1)
  - Unidentified work room photograph [Cream Meal packaging], undated (Box OM1)
  - Unidentified female portrait, undated (Box OM1)
  - Unidentified photograph [water tower in background], undated (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard, unidentified woman, undated (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard, unidentified adolescent girl, undated (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard, unidentified man, undated (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard, unidentified man, undated (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard, unidentified man, undated (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard, two unidentified children, undated (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard, unidentified infant, undated (Box OM1)
  - Photograph postcard, unidentified house [20 adults posed on porch and balcony], undated (Box OM1)
  - Unidentified men shaking hands under tree, undated (Box OM1)
  - Unidentified toddler, undated (Box OM1)
  - Unidentified toddler, undated (Box OM1)
  - Unidentified family portrait, undated (Drawer 70)
  - Unidentified church photograph [possibly San Diego, TX] (Drawer 70)
  - Southern Cement Products Company photograph [hand-tinted panoramic of work or stock yard] (Drawer 70)